which in theory are trying to do that are being constrained. But perhaps even more important, we heard before about the one percent, the 99 percent. If the state is thought about in this more strategic way, as one of the lead players in the value creation mechanism, because that's what we're talking about, right? Who are the different players in creating value in the economy, and is the state's role, has it been sort of dismissed as being a backseat player? If we can actually have a broader theory of value creation and allow us to actually admit what the state has been doing and reap something back, it might just be that in the next round, and I hope that we all hope that the next big revolution will in fact be green, that that period of growth will not only be smart, innovation-led, not only green, but also more inclusive, so that the public schools in places like Silicon Valley can actually also benefit from that growth, because they have not. Thank you. (Applause)
que en teoría están tratando de hacerlo están siendo limitados. Pero quizás aún más importante, hemos oído antes del 1 %, del 99 %. Si el Estado se pensara de esta forma estratégica, como uno de los jugadores principales en el mecanismo de creación de valor, porque de eso estamos hablando, ¿sí? Quiénes son los diferentes actores en la creación de valor en la economía y el papel del Estado, y cómo se lo ha relegado a un segundo plano. Si podemos tener una teoría más amplia de creación de valor que nos permita admitir lo que el Estado ha estado haciendo y obtener algo a cambio, podría ser en la próxima ronda, y espero que todos esperemos que la siguiente gran revolución de hecho sea ecológica, que ese período de crecimiento no solo sea inteligente, basado en la innovación, no solo ecológico, sino también más inclusivo, para que las escuelas públicas en lugares como Silicon Valley pueden beneficiarse de ese crecimiento, porque no lo han hecho. Gracias. (Aplausos)